A Guide to the Director's correspondence of the the Virginia State Lottery Dept., 1988-1992.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lottery Dept., Virginia State, Director's correspondence
1988-1992.
The Library of Virginia
34245, 34717
Virginia. State Lottery Dept.
12 cubic feet
Biographical/Historical Information
Based on the passage of a state-wide referendum, the General Assembly approved the establishment of a state-operated lottery and the creation of a State Lottery Board within a Department of Lottery, on March 27, 1987. The Department of Lottery is an independent agency of the Commonwealth, exclusive of the legislative, executive, or judicial branches of government. It includes a five-member board appointed by the Governor to serve at his pleasure, subject to legislative confirmation. The Director, also appointed by the Governor with legislative confirmation, is responsible for supervising and administering the operation of the lottery in accordance with state law. All profits from Virginia Lottery ticket sales go to K-12 public education. Lottery Dept. headquarters are located in Richmond, Va., with regional offices located in Abingdon, Fairfax, Farmville, Hampton, Harrisonburg, and Roanoke, Va.
Scope and Content
These records document the planning, direction, and implementation of commission programs and are evidence of actions and policy decisions. Includes director's correspondence, vendor files.
Various arrangements. Records have been kept in their original order.
Acquisition Information
Accession 34245 was transferred by the Virginia State Lottery Dept., August 20, 1992.
Accession 34717 was transferred by the Virginia State Lottery Dept., September 12, 1994.
Contents List
- Director's correspondence, 1988-1990 (Accession 34245)., Extent: 7 cubic feet (7 boxes)
  - Attorney General, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Chronological correspondence files, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Lottery meeting notes - Austin, TX, 1988. (Box 1)
  - General Assembly inquiries, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Correspondence, General, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Correspondence for signature of G. Baliles, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Correspondence for signature of H. Benson Dendy, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Correspondence for signature of A. B. Fogarty, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Correspondence for signature of R. B. Jones, Jr., 1988. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Correspondence for signature of K. W. Thorson, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Licensing recommendation letters, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Lottery Workplans, 1988. (Box 1)
  - National Association of State Provisional Lotteries (NASPL) Conference materials, 1988. (Box 1)
  - On-line First Study Report, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Public opinion letters, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Revenues, General Use of, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Speech files (Kenneth W. Thorson), 1988. (Box 1)
  - Weekly Division Reports, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Informal hearing files, 1989-1990. (Box 2)
  - Advertising - City/County Resolutions, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Attorney General corrspondence, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Chronological correspondence, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Endorsements / Recommendations for on-line terminals, 1989. (Box 3)
  - General Asembly inquiries, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Legislative proposals, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Licensing recommendation letters, 1988-1989. (Box 3)
  - Lottery press releases, 1988-1989. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1989. (Box 3)
  - National Association of State Provisional Lotteries (NASPL) - Boston, MA, 1989. (Box 3)
  - National Association of State Provisional Lotteries (NASPL) - Portland, OR, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Public Gaming Regulations - Lottery Marketing Seminar, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Public Gaming Resolutions - Lottery Expo Conference - Hiton Head, SC, 1989. (Box 3)
  - Project Team meeting minutes, 1989. (Box 4)
  - Public opinion, 1989. (Box 4)
  - Sales Dept. - General correspondence, 1989. (Box 4)
  - Sales - Goldstrike Operation, 1989. (Box 4)
  - Speech files (Kenneth W. Thorson), 1989. (Box 4)
  - State Agency Group Leaders, 1989. (Box 4)
  - Steering Committee meeting minutes - Lottery Systems Dept., 1989. (Box 4)
  - Warehouse space - Headquarters, 1989. (Box 4)
  - Weekly Division Reports, 1989. (Box 4)
  - Weekly Reports, 1989. (Box 4)